Yeah.
Do you have your handkerchief? Your ticket?
A nice pair of shoes?
The first time I met him
On a hot summer day,
I got lost in the forest of the mountain god,
which was said to be where spirits lived.
After running around searching for an exit
he appeared before me.
Hey! Shorty!
Why are you crying?
S-Sorry.
Y-You're really not human after all...
No human would hit a child like that!
If I get touched by a human,
that's the end.
I-I'm sorry.
Here, shorty.
Grab the other end.
You... aren't afraid.
Never mind.
If you go straight, you'll hit the mountain path.
Bye.
I'm Takegawa Hotaru.
You?
It's Gin.
Hotaru!
Ah, Uncle!
Hotaru, you idiot!
If you go into the forest on your own and get hurt, what are you gonna do?
Uncle.
Huh?
Is it true that there are spirits living in that forest?
Oh, the mountain god's forest... Who knows.
That's what they say.
In the end, I never met any, but I had the feeling I'd occasionally spot something from the corner of my eye.
And now that I think about it, Iwa said she and her friends went and had fun at a summer festival in the forest.
But there's no way the villagers would've held a festival in the forest.
So then, whose festival could it have been?
This is the forest where the mountain god and spirits live.
Set foot within, and you'll lose your way and be lost forever.
I didn't think you'd really come back.
It's a bit hot here.
Don't worry.
I'll see you out of here again.
Gin.
Is that so?
Human child.
Please don't touch Gin's skin.
If you do, I'll eat you!
Why do you wear a mask?
Thank you!
Even though it was silly,
Did Gin fall asleep?
Ah, sorry!
Ouch!
Attacking someone while they're asleep... You sure are a scary little lady.
I'm sorry, but
Why are you wearing that mask?
If I don't wear this mask,
I don't look like a spirit, do I?
You're weird.
Um, Gin.
Will you be able to come again next year?
Yeah!
It's cold!
You're weird.
Of course the water is cold.
Gin!
It's dangerous, Gin.
Yes.
Where are you?
What're you doing?
At least when I'm around,
can you take off your mask every once in a while?
That's fine,
but is there a reason?
That was close.
Yeah...
I'm sorry, Hotaru.
Are you okay?
No matter what, don't ever touch me, okay?
Okay?
I visited the forest.
Gin! I'm here again this year.
Somehow,
you're starting to look like a woman.
I am a woman.
Yeah.
Huh?
This is...
Nothing.
a lot of my elementary school friends are in the same classes, so it doesn't really feel like anything changed.
Our ages are gradually getting closer.
But rather than that...
Gin ages much more slowly than humans.
Here I go!
but Gin is almost the same as the day we met.
Oh, Hotaru.
I cut some watermelon. Let's eat.
I don't know,
but they said I'll still be here until the afternoon.
If it continues like this, then winter will be freezing.
Is it like that?
It's like that.
Since this area's located between mountains and the ocean's far away,
the temperature difference between summer and winter is huge.
A scarf?
Bye!
Okay.
See you next year!
Takegawa?
Shouldn't you be heading to your next class soon?
Okay! Thanks.
Thank you for the food.
What?
I didn't eat anything!
Jeez. I'm gonna take a bath!
Takegawa.
Ta-ke-ga-wa.
Oh, good morning.
Good morning.
There, near your feet. It's frozen.
You'll slip. It's dangerous.
It's cold today.
Haven't you been a little out of it lately?
see Gin.
Is that your new uniform?
Yeah.
You don't come running at me anymore these days.
I learned my lesson after all those beatings.
Then I can be with you more.
In autumn,
winter,
spring...
Always.
Right?
Let me tell you about myself.
I'm no longer human.
I'd only just been abandoned, so I cried helplessly
as if to call back the parents who left me.
So that I never move on.
I'm like a ghost.
Hotaru.
It's okay if you forget about me.
A body that's maintained by magic is very weak.
If it touches a real human body,
the spell will break and the body will disappear.
It's just like snow, isn't it?
Gin,
I thought of you during winter.
Even during autumn
Don't forget.
even still,
The nuance is completely different!
Nuance?
But tonight, can you sneak out of your house?
I've wanted to go with you for a long time.
I-I want to go!
Meet me at eight at our usual place.
And I'll protect you, Hotaru.
When you say things that, it makes me want to glomp you.
Are they all disguised as humans?
That's right. Impressive, isn't it?
Hotaru.
Tie this around your wrist.
You'll get lost.
Here you go.
Look! That kid has a tail!
Wow, that was so weird!
Everyone went all out with their disguises, didn't they?
It was like a mimicking competition!
Is it like this every year?
Yeah, every time summer comes around...
I can no longer wait for summer to come around.
When I'm away from you, even though I can't be around crowds, I want to go see you.
That mask...
Have it.
He probably won't come to that place next summer.
This is definitely our last...
Wait!
Yeah. Thank you!
Be careful, okay?
Was that boy a human?
I love you.
Yeah.
I love you, too.
Hotaru. Thank you.
I probably won't be able to
My tears will be overflowing.
So, let's go.
m 1920 960 l 1920 1080 l 0 1080 l 0 960 l 1920 960
The cicadas laugh out in song
to the red evening sunset
The way back home is long
but I promised to come here again tomorrow
The summer is in full bloom
I thought the tale would never end
The summer flies by
to hide away its treasures till next year
I'll never ever forget
to my boring everyday life
And look! Summer is here again
making you look more beautiful than ever