Hey, put on a hat. You'll get heat stroke.
The first time I met him
he appeared before me.
No human would hit a child like that!
Never mind.
Hotaru!
Ah, Uncle!
Man, that takes me back!
This is the forest where the mountain god and spirits live.
Set foot within, and you'll lose your way and be lost forever.
You came.
I didn't think you'd really come back.
Oh! Is that a fox?
Did Gin fall asleep?
I'm sorry, but
you were pretending to sleep, weren't you?
So I have to go home tomorrow.
Gin!
It's dangerous, Gin.
At least when I'm around,
Yeah...
I'm sorry, Hotaru.
Are you okay?
No matter what, don't ever touch me, okay?
The next summer and the summer after that
I visited the forest.
Somehow,
Where's Mom?
Is that so?
Ah, you're right!
Everyone left already.
I'll see you later.
Okay! Thanks.
You're done?
Oh, good morning.
Thank you.
see Gin.
Let me tell you about myself.
I'd only just been abandoned, so I cried helplessly
It's such a fragile thing.
How long can you—
Something that disappears when touched...
It's just like snow, isn't it?
But tonight, can you sneak out of your house?
I've wanted to go with you for a long time.
Are they all disguised as humans?
Who?
Shall we go?
Here you go.
That mask...
Have it.
This is definitely our last...
He finally got to be hugged by a human.
to the red evening sunset
The way back home is long
making you look more beautiful than ever