Yeah.
Do you have your handkerchief? Your ticket?
A nice pair of shoes?
Jeez. I've been going there every year, so I'll be all right.
It's alright! I'm fine.
The first time I met him
was when I was six.
To the Forest of Firefly Lights
On a hot summer day,
I got lost in the forest of the mountain god,
he appeared before me.
Why are you crying?
If a human touches me, I'll disappear.
But... what do you mean by disappear?
If I get touched by a human,
that's the end.
Grab the other end.
You're lost, aren't you?
I'll lead you out of the forest.
Thank you!
It's just like going on a date!
Not a very romantic one...
Bye.
Are you always going to be here?
If I come back here, can we meet again?
This is the forest where the mountain god and spirits live.
Set foot within, and you'll lose your way and be lost forever.
You shouldn't come here.
That's what the villagers say, right?
I'm Takegawa Hotaru.
You?
Anyway, I'll be back tomorrow with a thank-you present!
Bye!
Hotaru, you idiot!
Uncle.
Huh?
Is it true that there are spirits living in that forest?
Oh, the mountain god's forest... Who knows.
That's what they say.
When I was little, I wanted to meet the spirits, so my friends and I often went into the forest.
So then, whose festival could it have been?
Man, that takes me back!
We were so stupid back when we were kids.
Set foot within, and you'll lose your way and be lost forever.
You came.
I didn't think you'd really come back.
You...
You waited for me!
Sorry.
It's a bit hot here.
Shall we go somewhere cooler?
What?
Don't worry.
I'll see you out of here again.
Gin.
Is that a human child?
Is that so?
Human child.
He transforms to scare people, but he's all bark and no bite.
Never mind me.
That's why I waited for you.
Over here, over here!
There.
Even though it was silly,
Ah, sorry!
Ouch!
Attacking someone while they're asleep... You sure are a scary little lady.
Why are you wearing that mask?
If I don't wear this mask,
I don't look like a spirit, do I?
You're weird.
Um, Gin.
I won't be able
to come here tomorrow.
I told you about it before, right?
So I have to go home tomorrow.
Will you be able to come again next year?
became something I looked forward to.
Gin waited for our promised summer.
Gin!
It's dangerous, Gin.
Yes.
Gin.
Be careful.
Two summers passed. Then three.
What're you doing?
At least when I'm around,
can you take off your mask every once in a while?
That's fine,
but is there a reason?
Not really, but—
Okay?
No matter what!
I visited the forest.
Gin! I'm here again this year.
Ta-da!
I've become a fifth grader.
Somehow,
you're starting to look like a woman.
I am a woman.
Yeah.
Huh?
This is...
a lot of my elementary school friends are in the same classes, so it doesn't really feel like anything changed.
Like this?
Yeah, yeah. When I start running, let go, okay?
Here I go!
As the years go by, my appearance changes,
but Gin is almost the same as the day we met.
Oh, Hotaru.
I cut some watermelon. Let's eat.
Okay. Yay!
Where's Mom?
Out shopping with your aunt.
They went to buy gifts for friends in Yokohama.
What time are you taking the bullet train tomorrow?
I don't know,
but they said I'll still be here until the afternoon.
Is that so?
If it continues like this, then winter will be freezing.
Is it like that?
It's like that.
Since this area's located between mountains and the ocean's far away,
could probably freeze the mountain god himself.
Um, Uncle...
A scarf?
Yep!
Please use it in the winter, okay?
Bye!
Okay.
See you next year!
Takegawa?
Shouldn't you be heading to your next class soon?
Ah, you're right!
Everyone left already.
I'll see you later.
Okay! Thanks.
Thank you for the food.
What?
You're done?
Ah, you probably ate before dinner, didn't you?
If you snack, you'll gain weight.
I didn't eat anything!
Takegawa.
Ta-ke-ga-wa.
You'll slip. It's dangerous.
Thank you.
Is that your new uniform?
Yeah.
Time really flies, doesn't it?
You're already in high school, huh.
Yup.
You don't come running at me anymore these days.
I learned my lesson after all those beatings.
I'm looking forward to it.
In three years, when I graduate, I plan on looking for a job here.
Then I can be with you more.
In autumn,
winter,
spring...
Always.
Right?
Hotaru.
Let me tell you about myself.
I'm not a spirit.
But,
I'm no longer human.
It seems like I was once a human,
but when I was a baby,
but the mountain god appeared and cast a spell that allowed me to continue living.
I'm like a ghost.
Hotaru.
If it touches a real human body,
the spell will break and the body will disappear.
It's just like snow, isn't it?
Gin,
I thought of you during winter.
don't forget about me.
Don't forget.
even still,
until then,
let's stay together.
Spirit festival?
The nuance is completely different!
Nuance?
When you were little, I thought you might get scared, so I didn't invite you.
Meet me at eight at our usual place.
But a festival filled with spirits sounds a little unnerving...
On top of that, it's at night.
Don't worry.
On the outside, it's not very different from a human festival.
It's supposed to mimic human festivals, after all.
And I'll protect you, Hotaru.
When you say things that, it makes me want to glomp you.
Do it.
It's true. It's just like a human festival.
Are they all disguised as humans?
That's right. Impressive, isn't it?
I've heard that sometimes even humans unknowingly mix in.
Who?
It's just like going on a date!
This is a date.
Shall we go?
Yeah.
Here you go.
Ew, a couple!
Hey!
Look! That kid has a tail!
I-I'm sorry!
Wow, that was so weird!
When I'm away from you, even though I can't be around crowds, I want to go see you.
This is definitely our last...
Wait!
Yeah. Thank you!
Be careful, okay?
Gin?
Gin!
Come here, Hotaru!
I can finally touch you.
I love you.
Yeah.
I love you, too.
Hotaru. Thank you.
Gin wanted to touch a human.
My tears will be overflowing.
But this warmth in my hands and these summer memories will live on in my heart.
So, let's go.
Let us go.
m 1920 960 l 1920 1080 l 0 1080 l 0 960 l 1920 960
The cicadas laugh out in song
to the red evening sunset
The way back home is long
but I promised to come here again tomorrow
The summer is in full bloom
The crows too took flight
and went somewhere far, far away
The summer flies by
to hide away its treasures till next year
I'll never ever forget
those golden summer days
That summer which brought joy
to my boring everyday life
And look! Summer is here again
to help me keep my promise of that day
making you look more beautiful than ever